Hello English learners.
英语学习者你们好。
Welcome back to another advanced lesson here at EnglishPod.
欢迎回到 EnglishPod 的又一节高级课程。
My name is Marco.
我是 Marco。
And I'm Erica.
我是 Erica。
And today we're going to be back in the office.
今天我们要回到办公室场景。
That's right.
没错。
We are listening in as somebody gets a little bit of trouble from their boss for being a
我们将听到有人因为项目进度有点落后而被老板训斥。
bit late on a project.
有点晚了。
Alright so we're going to be at the office.
好的，所以我们要在办公室里。
Somebody misses a deadline and so well how do you handle the situation?
有人错过了截止日期，那么你该如何处理这种情况？
What can you do to explain yourself?
你能做些什么来解释自己？
And what language can you actually use to talk about missed deadlines and late work?
实际上你可以用什么语言来谈论错过截止日期和工作延误？
Alright so let's see why this person missed the deadline and let's find out what happens.
好的，让我们看看这个人为什么错过了截止日期，并看看发生了什么。
And so I just wanted to check in with you and find out where we are with this project.
我只是想跟你确认一下，看看这个项目的进展如何。
As you know, you missed a fairly significant deadline last week and this will negatively
你知道，上周你错过了一个相当重要的截止日期，这会对团队推进项目下一阶段的能力产生负面影响。
impact the team's ability to move forward with the next stages of this project.
影响团队推进项目下一阶段的能力。
I know.
我知道。
I'm really sorry that I missed the deadline.
我很抱歉错过了截止日期。
But really it wasn't my fault.
但真的不是我的错。
You see we had all of these unexpected technical problems at the last minute and I couldn't
你看，我们在最后一刻遇到了所有这些意想不到的技术问题，我无法
get into the database and extract the kind of information that I needed for the data
进入数据库并提取我进行数据分析所需的那种信息。
analysis.
数据分析。
You know if the tech guys would have done their job and kept the CRM stable then I wouldn't
你知道，如果技术人员做好他们的工作，保持 CRM 稳定，我就不会
have missed my deadline.
错过我的截止日期。
Oh come on!
哦，得了吧！
An excuse like that is tantamount to lying.
像这样的借口无异于撒谎。
You're essentially blaming the tech team for your time management issues rather than accepting
你本质上是在把你的时间管理问题归咎于技术团队，而不是接受
responsibility for the fact that you were procrastinating for the past two weeks.
你过去两周一直在拖延的事实。
No I'm not trying to pass the buck here.
不，我不是想推卸责任。
I know it was me who was ultimately responsible for getting this done.
我知道最终负责完成这件事的人是我。
But the thing is I could have finished on time if the system hadn't gone down.
但问题是，如果系统没有宕机，我本可以按时完成的。
And you know with everything I've got going on now I can't afford to waste time dealing
而且你知道，我现在手头有这么多事，我可没时间浪费在处理
with technical problems.
技术问题上。
I've got a lot on my plate and there are only 24 hours in a day.
我手头事情很多，一天只有 24 小时。
I'm not going to accept this excuse.
我不会接受这个借口。
You're using these small technical glitches as a crutch and trying to rationalize the
你把这些小的技术故障当作拐杖，试图合理化
fact that you've missed your deadline.
你错过截止日期的事实。
Look we have standards and I expect you to live up to those standards.
听着，我们有标准，我希望你能达到这些标准。
No more phony excuses.
别再找虚假的借口了。
If you're in over your head you tell me.
如果你应付不来，就告诉我。
No more missed deadlines.
别再错过截止日期了。
Now I want that data on my desk by 9 a.m.
现在，我要那份数据在早上 9 点之前放在我桌上。
Well it sounds like this guy isn't really accepting a lot of the responsibility for
嗯，听起来这家伙并没有真正承担很多责任
his missed deadline.
对于他错过截止日期这件事。
Exactly.
没错。
Well apparently he's explaining that it wasn't only his fault.
嗯，显然他在解释这不全是他的错。
Yeah.
是的。
So some technical problems but you know he used a lot of pretty pretty interesting language
所以是一些技术问题，但你知道他用了很多非常有趣的语言，
and I think it'll help us to look at that now in Language Takeaway.
我认为现在在“语言要点”环节看看这些会很有帮助。
Language Takeaway.
语言要点。
All right.
好的。
So on Language Takeaway today we have five words and let's start with the first one.
那么在今天的“语言要点”中，我们有五个单词，让我们从第一个开始。
All right.
好的。
Well the boss is not really happy with the excuse that the employee was giving and he
嗯，老板对员工给出的借口不太满意，他
said an excuse like that is tantamount to lying.
说像这样的借口无异于撒谎。
Tantamount.
无异于。
Tantamount to something.
无异于某事。
OK so if an excuse like that is tantamount to lying what is what is he trying to say
好的，所以如果一个借口无异于撒谎，他在这里想表达什么
here.
意思？
Basically it's the same as or it's almost the same as.
基本上就是等同于，或者几乎等同于。
So similar to.
所以类似于。
So if I say tantamount to something else how would I use it.
所以如果我说“无异于”其他东西，我该怎么用？
You know Marco taking my computer without asking is tantamount to stealing.
你知道，Marco，未经允许拿我的电脑无异于偷窃。
OK so even though I'm not actually stealing it or taking it home with me.
好的，所以即使我实际上没有偷它或把它带回家。
Yeah.
是的。
It is almost like stealing.
这几乎就像偷窃。
Yeah.
是的。
And the interesting grammatical thing here is that we almost always use a gerund right
这里一个有趣的语法点是，我们几乎总是在后面用动名词，对吧？
after so tantamount to verb ing.
所以是“无异于 + 动词 ing”。
OK tantamount to stealing tantamount to lying tantamount to killing.
好的，“无异于偷窃”、“无异于撒谎”、“无异于杀人”。
OK.
好的。
Well on that happy note let's go on to our next word.
嗯，带着这个愉快的点，我们继续下一个词。
Now the boss was really unhappy with the employee for procrastinating.
现在老板对员工拖延非常不满。
Procrastinating.
拖延。
So the verb is to procrastinate.
所以动词是“拖延”。
And when you procrastinate you say I'll do it later I'll do it tomorrow.
当你拖延时，你会说“我晚点再做”、“我明天再做”。
OK so you kind of delay things or you leave it for another day.
好的，所以你有点推迟事情，或者留到另一天。
Yeah.
是的。
All right.
好的。
Very good.
非常好。
So to procrastinate.
所以是“拖延”。
A favorite verb amongst college students.
大学生最喜欢的动词。
I actually thought for a little while that procrastinate was to have babies.
我其实有一阵子以为“拖延”是生孩子。
Oh.
哦。
OK.
好的。
It's kind of similar.
有点相似。
What's the word.
那个词是什么？
Procreate.
生育。
So I thought procrastinate was like having babies like why are you procrastinating.
所以我以为“拖延”就像生孩子，比如“你为什么在拖延？”
And I'm like I'm not.
然后我说“我没有”。
Well glad you got that straight.
嗯，很高兴你搞清楚了。
So yes our listeners procrastinate is not the same as procreate.
所以是的，我们的听众，“拖延”和“生育”不一样。
OK.
好的。
I learned that the hard way.
我是通过惨痛教训学到的。
Yes.
是的。
Well it sounds like you had a little bit of a glitch in your understanding of language
嗯，听起来你在语言理解上有点小故障，
and that's our next phrase.
这就是我们的下一个短语。
So in the dialogue they were talking about some glitches with the system.
所以在对话中，他们谈到了一些系统故障。
A glitch in the system.
系统故障。
OK.
好的。
So a glitch.
所以是“故障”。
Now this is common among computers right.
这在电脑中很常见，对吧？
A glitch is an error.
故障就是错误。
Right.
对。
So when you're talking about a glitch and you're talking about computers it's an error
所以当你谈论故障，并且你在谈论电脑时，它是一个错误、
a mistake.
一个失误。
But we also use it to talk about any unexpected problem.
但我们也用它来谈论任何意想不到的问题。
A small unexpected problem.
一个小的意想不到的问题。
OK.
好的。
So a small glitch.
所以一个小故障。
Yeah.
是的。
There was a glitch in our plan and we arrived 10 minutes late.
我们的计划出了个小故障，我们迟到了 10 分钟。
Or I can say this movie has a glitch in the story.
或者我可以说这部电影的故事有个故障。
So there's a small problem in the story that doesn't make sense.
所以故事里有个小问题，说不通。
Exactly.
没错。
All right.
好的。
So the boss was blaming his lateness on these small technical glitches.
所以老板把他的延误归咎于这些小技术故障。
But the boss didn't believe this right.
但老板不相信这个，对吧？
The boss said you're trying to rationalize the fact that you missed the deadline.
老板说你在试图合理化你错过截止日期的事实。
OK.
好的。
To rationalize.
合理化。
So the boss is saying that he's trying to rationalize.
所以老板说他在试图合理化。
So that means is he trying to make sense of it.
那意味着他在试图让它说得通吗？
Well this is an interesting psychological word.
嗯，这是一个有趣的心理学词汇。
Because when you rationalize something you think about it or describe it like especially
因为当你合理化某件事时，你会思考或描述它，尤其是
some bad behavior in a way that makes it seem better or proper or more sensible.
一些不好的行为，以一种让它看起来更好、更恰当或更合理的方式。
So you're trying to convince yourself.
所以你在试图说服自己。
Yeah.
是的。
You're telling other people but you're also telling yourself that it's better.
你在告诉别人，但也在告诉自己它更好。
OK.
好的。
Or that you're right when you're actually wrong.
或者你是对的，而实际上你是错的。
Yes.
是的。
Yeah.
OK.
好的。
So he was trying to rationalize the fact that he missed the deadline.
所以他试图合理化他错过截止日期的事实。
So he was trying to explain to the boss and also kind of make himself believe that it
所以他试图向老板解释，同时也让自己相信
wasn't really his fault when it was.
这真的不是他的错，而实际上是他的错。
Now because this is a little bit of a difficult concept to understand I think we should hear
因为这是一个有点难理解的概念，我认为我们应该听一些
some examples.
例子。
Example one.
例子一。
You can't rationalize your son's behavior by saying he's going through a hard time.
你不能通过说他正在经历困难时期来合理化你儿子的行为。
Example two.
例子二。
As much as I tried I couldn't rationalize buying such an expensive pair of shoes.
尽管我努力了，我还是无法合理化买这么贵的一双鞋。
Example three.
例子三。
You know it was the wrong thing to do.
你知道那是错事。
Stop trying to rationalize it.
别再试图合理化它了。
OK.
好的。
So clear as daylight now this word rationalize.
所以现在这个词“合理化”非常清楚了。
All right.
好的。
In our final word.
最后一个词。
So the boss really wasn't happy with these excuses and he said no more phony excuses.
所以老板对这些借口非常不满，他说“别再找虚假的借口了”。
OK.
好的。
Phony.
虚假的。
P-H-O-N-Y.
P-H-O-N-Y。
Phony.
虚假的。
So phony is basically false or fake.
所以“虚假的”基本上就是假的或伪造的。
Right.
对。
So a phony statement.
所以一个虚假的陈述。
A phony watch.
一块假表。
OK.
好的。
A fake watch.
一块假表。
Yeah.
是的。
Not a Sony watch but a phony watch.
不是索尼表，而是假表。
A phony.
假的。
So a lot of great words in this dialogue but as you mentioned we also saw some very interesting
这个对话中有很多好词，但正如你提到的，我们也看到了一些非常有趣的
phrases that we can use in situations like this.
短语，可以在这种情况下使用。
So why don't we start now with Fluency Builder.
所以我们为什么不现在从“流利度构建”开始。
Fluency Builder.
流利度构建。
Well you know one of the interesting things about English is that we have a lot of ways
嗯，你知道英语的一个有趣之处在于我们有很多方法
to make things sound more direct less direct harder or softer and in this dialogue there
让事情听起来更直接、更不直接、更硬或更软，在这个对话中
are a few examples of how we use softening words to but just to do the opposite to actually
有几个例子说明我们如何使用软化词，但恰恰相反，实际上
make it a little strong.
让它更强硬一点。
OK.
好的。
So why don't we start with the first paragraph in the first part of the dialogue.
所以我们为什么不从对话的第一部分的第一段开始。
He said you missed a fairly significant deadline.
他说“你错过了一个相当重要的截止日期”。
A fairly significant deadline.
一个相当重要的截止日期。
Now this word fairly kind of sort of.
现在这个词“相当”有点、算是。
So it's not very significant.
所以不是非常重要。
It's kind of significant.
是有点重要。
Yeah.
是的。
But in this context when when the person is saying it it just sounds a little bit softer
但在这个上下文中，当说话者说这句话时，它听起来有点柔和，
but your understanding is it's a very important deadline.
但你的理解是这是一个非常重要的截止日期。
OK.
好的。
A very important deadline.
一个非常重要的截止日期。
So another similar example of this is the boss was saying you're essentially blaming
另一个类似的例子是老板说“你本质上是在责怪
the tech team.
技术团队”。
OK.
好的。
You're essentially blaming.
“你本质上是在责怪”。
So essentially is like basically or pretty much.
所以“本质上”就像“基本上”或“差不多”。
So it sounds a little softer but what he's actually really saying is you're doing this.
所以听起来柔和一点，但他实际上真正说的是你在做这件事。
Right.
对。
So instead of saying you're blaming the tech team he adds this word essentially to kind
所以他没有说“你在责怪技术团队”，而是加了“本质上”这个词来
of say well basically you're saying it's their fault.
说“嗯，基本上你在说是他们的错”。
Yeah.
是的。
But the context or you understand that it's actually very direct and he's saying it's
但上下文或你的理解是，这实际上非常直接，他在说这是
your fault.
你的错。
Yeah.
是的。
So he's he's he's saying you're almost blaming the tech team but what he means is you're
所以他是在说，你几乎是在责怪技术团队，但他的意思是你在
blaming the tech team.
责怪技术团队。
Now our third phrase is very interesting because it's kind of like a saying.
现在我们的第三个短语很有趣，因为它有点像一句俗语。
That's right.
没错。
So the employee says I'm not trying to pass the buck here.
所以员工说：“我不是想推卸责任。”
I'm not trying to pass the buck here.
我不是想推卸责任。
I'm not trying to pass the buck.
Now what's the buck.
那么“buck”是什么？
A dollar bill.
一美元钞票。
So he's well I understand that he's saying I'm not trying to blame somebody else or pass
所以他是在说，我明白他的意思是他不是在责怪别人或把
the blame on to someone else.
责任推给别人。
But you can think about it like this.
但你可以这样想。
Like imagine he had some fake or phony money right.
就像想象他有一些假币或伪钞，对吧。
And he wants to pass that on to the next person so he doesn't get in trouble.
他想把这些传给下一个人，这样他就不会惹上麻烦。
OK.
好的。
So I'm not trying to pass the buck.
所以我不是想推卸责任。
I'm not trying to pass the blame put the responsibility on someone else.
我不是想把责任推给别人，把责任转嫁出去。
Very good.
很好。
But you know what you know what he really means here.
但你知道他真正想表达的是什么吗？
What I am trying to do that because he knew.
我之所以这么做，是因为他知道。
He knew that it was a fake dollar bill.
他知道那是一张假美元。
Yeah.
是的。
And this is interesting as well because it's kind of like a metaphor.
这也很有趣，因为它有点像一种比喻。
He said the boss said you're using the small technical glitches as a crutch.
他说老板说：“你在用小的技术故障当拐杖。”
So using something as a crutch.
所以“把某物当拐杖”。
Now the crutch is a you know when you when you break your leg you use those wooden or
拐杖就是，当你摔断腿时，你用的那些木制或
metal sticks to walk with.
金属棍子来走路。
OK to help you walk.
好的，用来帮助你走路。
Yeah.
是的。
So the boss is basically saying you're using these technical glitches as an excuse or as
所以老板基本上是在说，你在用这些技术故障作为借口或
an aid to why you missed the deadline.
辅助理由，来解释你为什么错过了截止日期。
Yeah.
是的。
So if you think about it like this some people might say OK if you walk with a crutch then
所以如果你这样想，有些人可能会说，如果你拄着拐杖走路，
you you won't succeed.
你就不会成功。
Right.
对。
Because whatever.
因为不管怎样。
So this guy this employee is basically saying yes I know that I should meet deadlines but
所以这个员工基本上是在说，是的，我知道我应该按时完成任务，但
these these problems these glitches are like my crutch that make me not succeed.
这些问题、这些故障就像我的拐杖，让我无法成功。
OK.
好的。
So he's trying to just make excuses.
所以他只是在找借口。
So God Marco that is a little bit difficult to understand.
天哪，Marco，这有点难理解。
Do you think we should give a couple more examples.
你觉得我们应该再举几个例子吗？
Yeah I think I think some more examples would be very useful.
是的，我觉得再多举几个例子会很有用。
So let's listen to a couple of them now.
那我们现在来听几个例子。
Example one.
例子一。
I realized that I was using alcohol as a crutch to get through the day.
我意识到我过去把喝酒当作度过一天的拐杖。
Example two.
例子二。
I think Bill's very capable of being successful but he uses his disability as a crutch example
我觉得比尔完全有能力成功，但他把自己的残疾当作拐杖。例子
three.
三。
Stop using your weight as a crutch just because you're a bit fat doesn't mean you can't get
别再拿你的体重当拐杖了，你只是有点胖，并不意味着你不能找到
a great job.
一份好工作。
All right.
好的。
So a lot of great phrases great words and well I think it's time for us to listen to
所以有很多很棒的短语和词汇，我想是时候让我们最后
this dialogue for the last time and then we'll come back and talk about this aspect of meeting
听一遍这段对话了，然后我们再回来讨论关于按时完成任务
deadlines.
的这个方面。
And so I just wanted to check in with you and find out where we are with this project.
所以我想跟你确认一下，看看这个项目进展到哪了。
As you know you've missed a fairly significant deadline last week and this will negatively
你知道，上周你错过了一个相当重要的截止日期，这会负面
impact the team's ability to move forward with the next stages of this project.
影响团队推进项目下一阶段的能力。
I know I'm really sorry that I missed the deadline but really it wasn't my fault.
我知道，我很抱歉错过了截止日期，但这真的不是我的错。
You see we had all of these unexpected technical problems at the last minute and I couldn't
你看，我们在最后一刻遇到了所有这些意想不到的技术问题，我无法
get into the database and extract the kind of information that I needed for the data
进入数据库提取我进行数据
analysis.
分析所需的那种信息。
You know if the tech guys would have done their job and kept the CRM stable then I wouldn't
你知道，如果技术团队做好他们的工作，保持CRM系统稳定，我就不会
have missed my deadline.
错过截止日期了。
Oh come on.
哦，得了吧。
An excuse like that is tantamount to lying.
像这样的借口无异于撒谎。
You're essentially blaming the tech team for your time management issues rather than accepting
你基本上是在把你的时间管理问题归咎于技术团队，而不是接受
responsibility for the fact that you were procrastinating for the past two weeks.
你过去两周一直在拖延的事实。
No I'm not trying to pass the buck here.
不，我不是想推卸责任。
I know it was me who was ultimately responsible for getting this done.
我知道最终负责完成这件事的人是我。
But the thing is I could have finished on time if the system hadn't gone down.
但问题是，如果系统没有出故障，我本来可以按时完成的。
And you know with everything I've got going on now I can't afford to waste time dealing
而且你知道，我现在手头有这么多事，我可没时间浪费在
with technical problems.
处理技术问题上。
I've got a lot on my plate and there are only 24 hours in a day.
我手头事情很多，一天只有24小时。
I'm not going to accept this excuse.
我不会接受这个借口。
You're using these small technical glitches as a crutch and trying to rationalize the
你在用这些小的技术故障当拐杖，试图合理化
fact that you've missed your deadline.
你错过截止日期的事实。
Look we have standards and I expect you to live up to those standards.
听着，我们有标准，我希望你达到这些标准。
No more phony excuses.
别再找虚假的借口了。
If you're in over your head you tell me.
如果你应付不来，就告诉我。
No more missed deadlines.
不能再错过截止日期了。
Now I want that data on my desk by 9 a.m.
现在，我要你在早上9点前把数据放在我桌上。
This employee got in a lot of trouble for missing his deadline.
这个员工因为错过截止日期惹了大麻烦。
Exactly.
没错。
I think it's a very important aspect of not only Western culture but also in general assuming
我认为这不仅在西方文化中，而且在普遍情况下，是一个非常重要的方面：当
guilt when it's your fault.
是你的错时，要承担责任。
In this case we saw that the employee didn't really want to accept the fact that it was
在这个案例中，我们看到员工并不想接受这是
his fault.
他的错这个事实。
He didn't say yeah I know it was me I'm sorry and this is my plan to fix it.
他没有说：“是的，我知道是我的错，我很抱歉，这是我的补救计划。”
Now this is very important among cultures because in some cultures the aspect of losing
这在不同的文化中非常重要，因为在某些文化中，“丢面子”
face is so important right?
这个方面非常重要，对吧？
Right.
对。
So somebody may not really want to assume guilt or they have to because it's part of
所以有些人可能不想承担责任，或者他们必须承担，因为这是
the culture.
文化的一部分。
But what's the standard in North American business practice?
但北美商业实践中的标准是什么？
I would say that you would have to assume responsibility and take responsibility for
我会说，你必须承担责任，为你的行为负责，
your actions right and say yes it's my fault I did it but I'm going to get it fixed or
并说：“是的，是我的错，我做的，但我会解决它，或者
I'll do it or I'll make up for it.
我会去做，或者我会弥补。”
So some good business tips here today in this lesson.
所以今天这节课里有一些很好的商业建议。
Now remember if you have any questions about the language or want to tell us a little bit
现在记住，如果你对语言有任何疑问，或者想告诉我们
about how you assume responsibility in your culture visit our website at EnglishPod.com.
在你的文化中你是如何承担责任的，请访问我们的网站EnglishPod.com。
Right we're always there to help you out and until next time.
对，我们随时都在那里帮助你，直到下次再见。
Thanks for listening and goodbye!
感谢收听，再见！